searchpage.com 2015-12-18

# SearchPage

Effective Date: 27 August, 2012  

SearchPage Tab is certified as a Trusted Download Program by TRUSTe signifying that SearchPage Tab has been tested by TRUSTe for compliance with TRUSTe's TDP program requirements including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding SearchPage Tab, please contact us at SearchPage, 4115 St-Laurent Suite 300, Montreal, Quebec, H2W 1Y7, Canada or by email at [feedback@searchpage.com](mailto:feedback@searchpage.com) or by phone at 514-788-4710. If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

This privacy policy (the "Privacy Policy") explains the privacy practices of SearchPage™, a product of SearchPage, a Canadian-based company ("SearchPage", "we", "us" or "our") that apply to (i) the access and use of the [http://www.searchpage.com](http://www.searchpage.com/) website, and any related sub-domains, which are operated by SearchPage (the "Website"), (ii) download and use of our proprietary application (the "SearchPage Tab Application") and (iii) the provision by SearchPage of services through the Website and the SearchPage Tab Application (the "Services").

SearchPage is committed to maintaining your privacy please read all the terms of this privacy policy so that you understand what type of personal information we collect and how we collect it, how we use it and to whom we disclose it.

  1. Consent. By using our website or the SearchPage Tab application, or by submitting personal information to us, you consent to SearchPage's collection, use and disclosure of such personal information in accordance with this privacy policy (as amended from time to time) and as permitted or required by law. If you do not agree with the terms of this Privacy Policy, do not provide us with any personal information or use any of the Services we offer on the Website or through the SearchPage Tab Application. You can withdraw your consent at any time by following the instructions described below in the Section "Questions?".
  2. Amendments. We may, from time to time, modify our Privacy Policy and will post a copy of the amended Privacy Policy on the Website, so we encourage you to review it periodically. If we make any substantial changes in the way we use your personal information, we will notify you with a prompt message the next time you open SearchPage Tab and will post a prominent notice on our website pages prior to the changes becoming effective. You will be deemed to have accepted the Privacy Policy, as amended, if you continue to use the Website after any amendments are posted on the Website.

A SPECIAL NOTE FOR PARENTS AND LEGAL GUARDIANS: SearchPage respects the U.S Children's Online Privacy Protection (COPPA) Act of 1998 and the guidelines of the Children's Advertising Review Unit (CARU) of the Council of Better Business Bureau, Inc. You can help by spending time online with your children and monitoring your children's online use. Please help us protect your child's privacy by instructing them never to provide personal information on this website or any other without your permission. If you are under 18, please be sure to read this policy with your parents or legal guardians and ask questions about things you do not understand. Children under 18 (U18) are prohibited from using the Services provided by SearchPage. 

  1. ### Information Collection.

    * We only collect personal information:
      * that you provide to us directly via the Website or the SearchPage Tab Application when you provide us feedback or send us requests for technical support. The collection is limited to the following information: name and email address;
    * SearchPage may also collect the following usage information, whether you are accessing the Website or use the SearchPage Tab Application: your IP address, SearchPage cookie information (see below), the date and time of your visit or use of the SearchPage Tab Application, the type of Internet browser or hardware device (computer or mobile/smartphone) you use, URLs of the pages you visit in order to give you search results and the URL of any other website that referred you to our Website. This information is not linked to you as an individual and is not usually regarded as personal information. We use your Mac Address, Drive Serial Number and Default Browser to assign you a unique identifier. SearchPage may also collect system information to diagnose and debug software issues. We collect a list of all add-ons you've installed to Firefox, Chrome, Internet Explorer and Safari in order to detect and solve add-on compatibility issues.
    * We do not collect any other personal information, and do not supplement with information from other sources.
  2. ### Use of the Information.

    * We use your personal information to send you information on our Services, offer you new features or new services, optimize the Services we provide to you, reply to requests for technical support or feedback, provide updates for the SearchPage Tab Application and provide customer services. Emails received for feedback or technical support will solely be used to respond to such communications.
    * If you no longer wish to receive emails from us you may follow the unsubscribe instructions in each of the email communications you receive.
    * We may use usage information (see above) to evaluate and improve the features, guest experience and functionality of our Website and/or the SearchPage Tab Application.
  3. ### Sharing and Disclosure.

    * We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy statement. SearchPage does not sell, rent, or share your personal information with other people, except to : 
      * service providers that facilitate our Services, provide any or all part of the Services on our behalf or help us improve the Services (for example, data storage, web analytics, mapping providers and maintenance service providers). These services providers have access to your personal information only for purposes of performing these tasks on our behalf;
      * law enforcement officials or governmental agencies (i) in response to their request; (ii) when permitted or required by law; or (iii) to establish our compliance with applicable laws, rules, regulations, or guidelines.
    * These providers and partners are prohibited from sharing or selling this information, and may not use this information for any purpose not enumerated in this section.
    * In addition, if SearchPage merges with another company, is subject to a corporate reorganization, sells or transfers all or part of the Website and/or the SearchPage Tab Application, its business assets or shares, or in the event of bankruptcy, it is possible that the personal information we possess may be sold, transferred or otherwise shared as part of that transaction. Also, SearchPage may decide to retain a copy of the information post transaction. 
      * You acknowledge that our service providers, as well as the members of your network who may receive your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy or applicable law may be located in countries which have a different level of data protection than in your home country.
      * We may also share with third parties certain aggregated non-personal information about our users (such as the type of web browser they use) so as to optimize our Services. Third parties are prohibited from sharing or selling this information, and may not use this information for any purpose not enumerated in this section. These may include data storage, web analytics, mapping providers, maintenance service providers and ad providers.
  4. ### Cookies, Third Party Cookies & Tracking Technologies.

    * A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier that is sent to your browser from a web site and stored locally. SearchPage may set and access certain cookies on your computer or your mobile device for the following reasons: 
      * so that we can provide you with customized content;
      * to keep track of preferences you specify while you are using our Services;
      * to provide general internal and user analytics;
      * to conduct research to improve the content of the Website, the SearchPage Tab Application and the Services; and
      * to assist in identifying possible fraudulent activities.
      * If you configure your browser to reject cookies, you may not be able to use certain or all of our Services.
    * Third Party Cookies. The use of cookies by our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, service providers is not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these cookies. Our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, service providers use session ID cookies to make it easier for you to use our Services.
    * We and our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company and service providers use software technologies such as clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs) that help us better manage content on our site and within our SearchPage Tab Application by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ personally identifiable information.
  5. ### Search Engine Logs Data

    * We store search engine logs data to improve your search results and to maintain the security of our systems. Analyzing logs data helps our engineers improve the relevancy of your search results.
    * Search engine logs are anonymized and do not contain any personal information.
  6. ### Posting on Users' Accessible Areas.

    * As a registered user, you may post, submit and exchange content and information on areas of the Website that are accessible to other users if you decide so. You should exercise caution if you choose to disclose personal information in a publicly accessible area. You are solely responsible for any personal information that you disclose and disseminate on publicly accessible areas.
  7. ### Editing or Correcting Your Personal Information.

    * You should advise us if you believe that your personal information is inaccurate.
    * You have the right (i) to ask for your personal information to be corrected or updated and (ii) to withdraw your consent to the use of your personal information. To do so, please contact us at [privacy@SearchPage.com](mailto:privacy@SearchPage.com) and remove our SearchPage Tab Application from your device.
    * We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.
  8. ### Security.

    * We restrict access to personal information to SearchPage employees and agents who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our Services.
    * We make commercially reasonable efforts to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of your personal information under our control. To help protect the confidentiality of your personal information, we take appropriate security measures (including physical security measures) and we operate secure data networks protected by industry standard firewall and password protection systems. We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at SearchPage, 4115 St-Laurent Suite 300, Montreal, Quebec, H2W 1Y7, Canada or by email at [privacy@SearchPage.com](mailto:privacy@SearchPage.com).
    * SearchPage has taken commercially reasonable steps to ensure that its service providers protect the confidentiality and security of your personal information, and to ensure that your personal information is processed only for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.
  9. ### Additional Policy Information.

    * Links to Other Sites. Our Site includes links to other Web sites (such as our blog) whose privacy practices may differ from those of SearchPage. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy statements. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy statement of any Web site you visit.
    * Testimonials. We post customer testimonials/comments/reviews on our web site or SearchPage Tab Application which may contain personally identifiable information. We do obtain the customer's consent via email prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial. If you want your testimonial removed please contact us at [privacy@SearchPage.com](mailto:privacy@SearchPage.com).
  10. ### Notification of Privacy Statement Changes.

    * We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you with a prompt message the next time you open SearchPage Tab and will also post a prominent notice on our website pages prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.
  11. ### Limitation of Liability.

    * YOU UNDERSTAND AND AGREE THAT ANY DISPUTE OVER PRIVACY IS SUBJECT TO THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY, AS WELL AS THE TERMS OF SERVICE FOR THE WEBSITE AND THE SEARCHPAGE TAB APPLICATION (INCLUDING THE LIMITATION OF LIABILITY PROVISIONS).
  12. ### Language.

    * The parties hereto acknowledge having expressly required that this Privacy Policy is to be drawn up in the English language. Les parties aux présentes reconnaissent avoir expressément exigé que la présente Politique relative à la protection des renseignements personnels soit rédigée en anglais.
  13. ### Questions?

    * If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy or, more generally, our privacy practices, you may contact us at SearchPage, 4115 St-Laurent Suite 300, Montreal, Quebec, H2W 1Y7, Canada or by email at [privacy@SearchPage.com](mailto:privacy@SearchPage.com).
